steamforged.com 2019-05-11

# Privacy & Cookies Policy — Steamforged Games

**HOW AND WHY WE USE PERSONAL DATA**

Under the Data Protection Legislation, we can only use your personal data if we have a proper reason for doing so. For example, because:

  * you have given us your consent;

  * it is necessary for the performance of a contract; or

  * it is necessary for our legitimate interests or those of a third party.

Consent

Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than:

  * to place cookies on your device (please see our [Cookie Notice](https://steamforged.com/cookies-policy) for further details);

  * to enable to you to take part in our events;

  * to send you our newsletters; and

  * to send you electronic marketing communication (if you are not our existing customer).

Where your permission is required, we will ask you for such consent separately and clearly. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by [contacting us](https://steamforged.com/contact-us-form/) or using the ‘unsubscribe’ link in our marketing emails. Even if we are not required to obtain your consent for marketing purposes, you can still opt-out of receiving marketing communications at any time, so you are still in control.

If you submit personal information for publication on our website or another location, we will publish and otherwise use that information in accordance with the permission which you grant to us.

Contract

We will use your personal data if we need to do it to perform our obligations under a contract with you, or if it is necessary for a contract which we are about to enter with you. For example, if we need to:

  * register you as a new customer or administer your account;

  * manage our relationship with you (e.g. to respond to your enquires or to notify you about changes to our services);

  * process or deliver your order; and

  * enable you to partake in a competition or a prize draw.

Legitimate interests

A _legitimate interest_ is when we have a business or commercial reason to use your information, so long as this is not overridden by your own rights and interests. We rely on our own, and/or or a third party’s legitimate interests, when we process your data for the following purposes:

  * to administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data);

  * to manage our relationship with you;

  * to manage payments;

  * to deal with your enquiries;

  * to ask you to leave a review or complete a survey;

  * to send you our updates or other electronic marketing communications (when you are our existing customer or have enquired about our products;

  * to engage with you though our social media profiles;

  * to fund our projects through crowdfunding campaigns run of Kickstarter and Backerkit to which you sign up;

  * to run our community events (e.g. conventions);

  * to increase our business or promote our brand through delivering relevant website content and advertisements to you and marketing communication;

  * to measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we provide to you;

  * to improve our website, products, services, marketing, and customer relationships and understanding;

  * to conduct web analytics; 

  * for the prevention and detection of fraud; and

  * to interact with you professionally (if you represent our supplier or other business party);

  * for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

We may ask you to confirm or update your marketing preferences if you instruct us to provide further services in the future, or if there are changes in the law, regulation, or structure of our business.
